AJ Bates

Full-Stack Developer

AJ Bates

Minneapolis, MN

612-743-3196 aj.bates2.92@gmail.com www.ajbates.dev

Summary

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer proficient in React, Node, Express, and Postgresql. I have 7 years of experience in customer service and sales, which has allowed me to develop my communication, teamwork, and problem-solving skills. I also have a strong interest in developing technology that genuinely helps people on a daily basis.

Recent Projects

SafeRes

December 2020 - PRESENT

The pandemic brought on a lot of hurdles to overcome in the service industry. One big issue was state-mandated reservations for all restaurants. I saw this as a great opportunity to create a user experience we haven't taken advantage of at the bar I worked at. Not only was this a way to contact people for their reservations, but it also makes it easier for us to contact people if there was an outbreak.

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, React-Spring, Node.js, Express.js, Postgresql

tips.

August 2020 - PRESENT

An app designed to help servers and bartenders keep better track of their income. I have worked in the service industry since I was twelve years old. One thing I didn't realize for a long time, is that if you actually know how much money you are making, the easier it is to save money. So I built this app to empower people in the service industry to take control of their income.

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, React-Router, Node.js, Express.js, Postgresql

BrewFinder

May 2020

A relatively simple app that utilizes the google map API to place data from an open-source brewery database. The user searches for a city and the app fetches data from the brewery database. That data is then used to place markers on the map. The user can then click on a marker to get the relevant information

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

Work Experience

JL Beers - Supervisor/Beertender

December 2015 - PRESENT, Burnsville, MN

Quickly became an invaluable employee and promoted to supervisor within the first year working there.

Developed multiple methods that are used to complete a lot of daily tasks, everything from closing the store down quickly and effectively, to spreadsheets used daily to easily split tips up and count down the safe.

Boonya Systems - Account Manager

July 2015 - December 2015, Bloomington, MN

Rebuilt companies website, still using it today, with a WordPress template that I modified to the best of my ability.

Built an email marketing campaign targeted at private practices focused on teaching them about HIPAA compliance as it relates to technology.

Lead multiple speaking engagements with private practice owners and managers teaching them how to better protect their patients sensitive information

Radiate Digital - Account Executive

March 2014 - July 2015

The first salesperson hired full time at a small web design/marketing company. The company was transitioning to sell custom-designed websites from the ground up at an affordable monthly price. \$99/month for a custom-designed website (no templates).

Acquired multiple big clients in my first couple of months, as well as multiple monthly based clients.

Education

Thinkful - Full-Stack Engineering Flex

February 2020 - December 2020

JavaScript-based intensive program that teaches both front-end and back-end technologies, which enabled me to build an app from wireframe and design to building out the database.

Technical Skills

Front-End

- jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

Frameworks

- React. React Native

Back-end

- Node.js, Express.js, Postgresql

Dev Tools

- Git, GitHub, Chrome Dev Tools, Postman, Google Analytics